Preliminary Guide to the Jim Grimsley Papers, 1970-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jim Grimsley papers 1970-2002 and undated
Grimsley, Jim
18 linear feet Extent: 5650 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
grimsley
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is restricted. Diaries/journals and personal correspondence are available to researchers only with permission of donor during his lifetime or until 1/1/2020; all other papers are open to researchers.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Purchased in 1997; addition received 2002.
Biographical Note
Author from Rocky Mount, NC, currently residing in Atlanta, GA.
Collection Overview
Collection includes personal journals (1973-1993); personal and professional correspondence (1970s-1996), handwritten notebooks containing the creative beginnings of his novels and plays, drafts of all of his writings (1970s - 1997); publicity, reviews, and publications by or about him in small magazines.
The addition (acc# 2003-0041)(3150 items, 5.0 linear feet) is minimally processed. Consists primarily of annotated typescripts, drafts and galleys of Grimsley's latest publications (including novels and plays), and provides an in-depth look at his recent work. Also includes personal correspondence (1982-2001); a journal and appointment books (1977-[1980s]); translations of his novels; and periodicals containing his contributions.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Grimsley, Jim. 1955-; Authors, American -- 20th century -- United States; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Family violence -- United States -- Fiction; North Carolina -- Fiction; Southern States -- Fiction; Homosexuality and literature; Gay men in literature; Gay men -- Fiction; Gay men's writings, American; Gay authors -- Correspondence; Boys -- United States -- Fiction; Dream Boy; Winter Birds
Contents of Collection
- Accession number: 1997-0055
  - Journals (Box 1)
    - 1973-1993
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Personal
    - Personal (Box 3)
    - Other correspondence, ca. 1982-1996 (Box 4)
  - Notebooks (Box 5)
    - 23 volumes
    - 19 volumes (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts (Box 7)
    - A- Dream Boy
    - Dream Boy-H (Box 8)
    - I-M (Box 9)
    - M-P (Box 10)
    - R- Winter Birds (Box 11)
    - Winter Birds-Y (Box 12)
  - Publicity (Box 13)
    - Printed Materials
    - Clippings
    - Videotapes
    - Printed Materials (Box 14)
- Accession 2003-0041
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    [Contents are restricted. Patrons must obtain written permission of the donor before use.]
    - Appointment books, 1980s
    - Personal correspondence, 1992-2000
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1982-2001
    - Journal, 1977-1978
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Asimov's Science Fiction
      - Oct./Nov. 2000 issue (2 copies), Mar. 2002 issue
        Issues include Grimsley stories.
    - Un Largo Camino
      Spanish translation of Comfort and Joy; Editorial Egales, 2001.
    - Hebrew translation of Comfort and Joy, 2001
    - Kirith Kirin
      Advanced reading copy, bound upside-down; Meisha Merlin, 2000.
    - Boulevard typescript, with editing marks
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Winter Birds typescript (partial)
    - Drag Queens of the 21st Century script rewrite, 1994-1995
    - Mr. Universe play galleys, 1993
    - Periodicals
      - American Theatre, Sept., Nov. 1990, Jan., Apr., Oct. 1991 issues
      - Men's Style, Dec. 1995
    - Copies of introductions to Grimsley's work by Kaye Gibbons and Craig Lucas, 1997
    - Comfort and Joy, typescript with editing marks, 1995-1998
    - Mr. Universe and Other Plays, setting manuscript and page proofs, 1998
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Mr. Universe and Other Plays, setting manuscript and page proofs, 1998 (cont.)
    - Comfort and Joy manuscript, 1997
    - Boulevard typescript with editing marks, undated
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Boulevard typescript with publisher's editing marks
    - Kirith Kirin typescript with editing marks, 1999
    - Boulevard typescript with comments by Elisabeth Lewis Corley, 2000
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Getting the News typescript with editing marks
    - Kirith Kirin typescript and page proofs with editing marks, 1999-2000
    - Into Greenwood typescripts (2 versions), one with editing marks
    - Thoroughly script, undated
      Early draft of play later retitled Free Market.
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - The Ordinary
      Printout of pages written Summer 1999 prior to rewrite, Summer 2000.
    - Typescripts
      - Into Greenwood, 2000
      - Reason to Live
    - Kirith Kirin cover
    - My Drowning, setting manuscript and page proofs, 1996-1997
    - In Berlin script (2 copies), one with editing marks, 1998, 2000
    - Boulevard
      Version printed April 1, 2000 before rewrites.
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Composition book with pages inserted: Rewrite of Kirith Kirin, Feb. 1998
    - Thoroughly script
    - Comfort and Joy, setting manuscript and page proofs, with editing marks, 1999-2000
    - The Ordinary typescript